# Leticia Jaquez Software Engineer

• MANCHESTER, NH

≥ letty.jaquez@gmail.com

9786542547

https://ljaquez.github.io/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/leticiajaquez/

## **Profile**

Detail-oriented, strategic, analytical thinker, and visionary with excellent written and verbal communication skills. Being a high school mathematics teacher for six years, with students of diverse backgrounds has equipped me with strong empathy, collaboration, and communication skills. It is my growth mindset that has propelled me to launch a new career in programming. I am always looking to learn new skills and apply them for problem-solving.

#### **Skills**

Mathematics • Technical Writing • R • Python • mySQL • JavaScript • HTML • CSS • React • Tableu Portuguese • Spanish

## **Education**

2022/02 – present Cambridge, MA

## Professional Certificate in Coding: Full Stack Development with MERN

Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)

- Build, test, and deploy a web application using the MERN stack
- Build, test, and deploy APIs
- Build, test, and deploy a front-end web application using React
- Setup Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Delivery (CD) pipelines to deploy a React application
- Troubleshooting and Debugging

Masters of Science in Education

2016 - 2017

Walden University

Minneapolis, MN

• Graduated Magna Cum Laude: 3.85 GPA

2011/10 – 2013/08 Minneapolis, MN **Bachelors of Science in Applied Psychology** 

Walden University

• Graduated Summa Cum Laude: 4.0 GPA

## **Professional Experience**

2019/06 – present Tyngsboro, MA

## **Mathematics Teacher**

Greater Lowell Technical High School

- **Teaching** Geometry to high school sophomores at all levels (Foundations, College Prep, & Honors) and diverse groups (special education, 504, and English Language Learner status) in person, hybrid, and virtually.
- **Developing and Implementing** Curriculum for Algebra 1, Geometry, Social Emotional Learning, and Financial Literacy.
- **Creating and Leading** professional development for faculty and staff in the use of technology for planning, teaching, and learning.
- Engaging Diverse Family Communities through being an English Language Learner Parent Liaison for the school.

2012/09 - 2019/06

Project Director
INTALPRO, Inc.

Bonao,

Dominican Republic

• **Creating and Managing** strategic annual plans, school charters, curricula, legal and financial documentation, informative publications, and grant proposals.

MAJORACHIEVEMENTS

- **Speaker** at the 2017 Biennial World Council for Gifted and Talented Children World Conference in Sydney, Australia.
- **Publishing** a chapter to be released this year in the book Gifted Children Around the World, edited by Dr. Joy Davis and Dr. James Moore III (Board Members of the National Association of Gifted Children).
- **Developing Post-Graduate Program** in Gifted Education at the Universidad Cátolica Nordestana (UCNE)
- Team Member in National Pact for Educational Reform (Pacto Nacional para la Reforma Educativa) in the Dominican Republic, which was signed at the presidential palace in April 2014.
- Establishing INTALPRO (Instituto de Talentos y Prodigios, Inc.) legally as a non-profit organization in both the US and the Dom. Rep

## Courses

Courses	
present	React - The Complete Guide (incl hooks, React Router, Redux)  Academind (through Udemy)
present	The Web Developer Bootcamp 2022  Udemy
present	The Ultimate MySQL Bootcamp  Udemy
2015/09	Introduction to R Programming  Microsoft (through Edx)
2015/09	Statistics and R for the Life Sciences  Harvard University (through $Edx$ )  Manipulating and analyzing large data sets.
2014/07	R Programming  John Hopkins University (through Coursera)
Awards	
2013	Presidential Commendation for Academic Achievement Walden University
2006	Scholar Finalist National Hispanic Recognition Program